Jih-Yang Tan

Lifelong Learner & Tenacious Activator

(604)-720-9933 jihyangt@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jihyangt

Profile

Marketing and Business Analytics graduate with experience working in high performing, fast-paced organizations. Experienced in managing and executing marketing campaigns. Research and segmenting customer markets for product improvements, measure and analyzing decision support analytics.

Technical Skills

Analytics · SQL · Python · Tableau · Excel · Oracle SQL · Adobe Analytics · BigQuery · R · XML · SAP Qualtrics

Web-Dev · HTML5 / CSS3 / JavaScript · Bootstrap4 · Wordpress

Other · Microsoft Office · Adobe Creative Suite · Google Analytics · Numpy · Pandas · SciKit-Learn · Plotly

Education

University of British Columbia

Vancouver, BC

Bachelor of Commerce in Marketing and Business Analytics

Sep 2016 - May 2020

UBC Marketing Course Hero Case Competition (1st Place out of 12 Teams)

Professional Experience

Department of Engineering - UBC

Vancouver, BC

Digital Communications and Data Analytics Assistant

Sep 2019 - May 2020

- Created and analyzed dashboards and data visualizations using Tableau and Python to optimize KPIs, then recommending solutions to management for review, resulting in 25% increased pages/session
- Launched and organized contents for Pay-Per-Click LinkedIn Marketing Campaign paired with A/B Testing and installed API to improve client acquisition, resulting in 33% increased Click-Through-Rate within 2 months
- Developed communications and marketing creatives for campus-wide promotions and events using Adobe Suite
- Produced industry reports in various engineering disciplines to assess student employment opportunities

Celtech
Marketing Analyst Intern

Selangor, KL May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Gathered information and examined user behavior and buying trends using SQL and Python to develop business plans and pricing strategies
- Planned, Budgeted, and Managed our Summer Google Ads Marketing campaign, the business result was a 28% increase in B2B sales within 4 months
- Developed the organization's website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Bootstrap on Wordpress that focuses on usability, this increased pages/session by 32% within 4 months

Department of Extended Learning - UBC

Vancouver, BC

Market Research Assistant

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Conducted a marketing budget allocation module for UBC's post-secondary program applicants
- Entered and analyzed applicant data for the previous 5 academic cohorts to create consumer segments

Projects

Real Earth Bounty

Vancouver, BC

BCom Capstone Project

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Created a marketing plan to launch 4 brand extension products, consisting of marketing strategy, competitive
 analysis, and customer analysis. The proposal was accepted and implemented into the client's business
- Conducted market research and analyzed purchase intentions on lead users to create data visualizations using Tableau and Oracle SQL to gather insight on customer purchase behavior and habits